

# MA MURUGAPAN MADHAVAN

# BIRTHDAY 01/11/1973

📞 00918939650933 😾 mamurugapan@gmail.com 💣 316 Al Mehri Building, 4<sup>™</sup> Floor

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly creative and skilled Videographer / Editor / Motion Graphic Designer with vast experience in all video production aspects. Extremely attentive to audio & video details. Very proficient in Computerised video and non linear editing systems, digital video mixer, Ability to simultaneously manage multiple projects with great professionalism.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Year(s) of Experience: 23

Current Level: Experienced (Non - Manager)

# Taj Television Network Ltd Ten Sports Dubai / India

08/2007 - Now: Videographer / Adobe Premier / Avid / FCP

- Live Studio / Instant Match Highlights for English Premier/ Scottish
- Dutch Soccer League for Goal Tv Hongkong / Starhub Singapore
- Instant Match Highlights Cricket / Daily Sports News Packaging
- Instant Highlights for US Open / Ryder Cup / Formula 1 / Hockey
- Beijing Olympics Sports News / WWE Raw, Smackdown
- VNR Packaging (Ten Sports activities) for SNTV
- Cricket / Football Ratings / Tour defrance
- Post-Production Promos / Sales AVs & Tag

### **EDUCATION**

#### Computer Point, Tiruchirappalli, Tamilnadu / India

Diploma Application Programming

01/1992 - 12/1992

### Tamilnadu State Board Of Secondary Education, Tiruchirappalli / India

 10th standard 04/1990 - 10/1991

#### LANGUAGES

English – Intermediate

### CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

# Nimbus Sports Channel, Mumbai / India

Avid Editor

Avid Editor

10/2006 - 08/2007

04/1996 - 10/2006

Instant Match Highlights Cricket

#### CNBC Asia Tv -18, Mumbai / India

Instant Match Highlights Cricket

- Live Studio Vision Mixing Special Shows like Inside India
- Production of Daily News Programming / Power Breakfast
- Business Lunch / Closing Bell
- Post-Production Promos / Sales AVs & Tags

# Hansa Vision B.B.D.O. Chennai / India

Avid Editor

07/1995 - 04/1996

- Documentaries / TV Commercials / Rangoli
- TV Serials (Fiction) Ippadik Thendral / Putham Puthu Kathaika

#### 7th Channel Communications Ltd, Chennai / India

Video Tape Editor 01/1993 - 07/1995

- Documentaries / TV Commercials
- Award Winning TV Series Marakamudiyavillai / Marandividu Mohana

### **Outside Freelancer Post-Production, Worldwide**

Photographer / Videographer / Editor

- Chennai High Court Conference Event / Lux Soap / Hindustan Lever (now 'Unilever') Nescafe / Rexona
- Amurtajan / Henko Kalyani Silks / Hayagrivas Silks, Gemini Color Film / Dena Bank / Kent Cars /
- BPL Products LIC (Life Insurance Corporation Of India) Prince Jewellery / Khazana Jewellery / Rmkv Emale
- ATN Channel Miss World 1996, Bollywood Shows / Wipro Shikai / Film Trailer Tamil Hindi Malayalam
- Photographer Marriage Events / Music Video Award Winning Vairamuthu's Kavaithi Parungal
- Documentaries Tisco / Sharpline groups / Murugappa Groups
- Showreel link Below ):

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j1tJpUWMx1A

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JNSP4H8aPuk

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h2pHYupxyVo

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KH-zRlhJb9U

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bgFt3NqTvJU

# **SKILLS**

- Adobe Premier Pro / Color Grading / Pinnacle Liquid Chrome HD
- Avid Media Composer / Avid Interplay / Avid ISIS Media Management
- HD Processes / Media Encoding / Transcoding & Video Processing
- Apple Final Cut Pro / After Effects / EVS Editing Replays with Mulitcam
- Harris Velocity ESX / Sony Vegas Video Editing
- Autodesk Smoke online Editing / Quantel Editbox & SQ
- Knowledge of Ross Video Production Switcher / Vizrt / Newtek

# AUDIO / DECKS / A-B ROLL EDIT CONTROL / VIDEO SWITCHER

- Avid Pro Tools
- Sony Low-band & High-band / Sony Digital Betacam / Dv Deks
- Sony 450 Edit Control / PVE 500 & BVE 2000 A-B Roll Edit Control Video Switcher
- Sony BVS 3200 Component Switcher / DFS 300 Switcher
- Alladdin Pinnacle / Ampex Ado 100 FX / VPS 300 Video Production System

#### CAMERAS GREEN SCREEN STUDIO LIGHTING

Sony XDCam Ex1 / Sony DvCam PD-175 / Nikon & Canon Dslr / Arri Lighting

## SOCIAL MEDIA PLATFORMS

Facebook - Twitter - Youtube - Instagram - Pinterest - Microsoft Office Suite

#### PERMANENT ADDRESS

No Q2 Nutech Solitare Apts Flat d 2<sup>nd</sup> Floor 86<sup>th</sup> Street, Ashok Nagar, Chennai, India

Email: <a href="mailto:murugapan@hotmail.com">murugapan@hotmail.com</a> / Skype: Ma Murugapan Madhavan / Mobile: 00971501847689

# **REFERENCES**

Danny Menken – Group Managing Director, Eleven Sports Network, Netherlands
Peter Hutton - Director, Global Live Sports & Programming at Facebook
Nine Revenue Director Media Breduction & Operations Liverge of Facebook

Nina Berry - Director Media Production & Operations, Liverpool Football Club United Kingdom

Rippy Chhabra - Deputy Vice President Editing, Taj Television Network Ltd, Dubai